なんば　むった
へいさ
(南波六太)＜閉鎖ボックスでの
試験も あと➡
In a few days, our sealed box exam will end.
ジャクサ
数日で終了｡ここでＪＡＸＡは
わざとトラブルを起こせという➡
JAXA has chosen now to issue orders that will stir up trouble.
指令を みんなに与えてきた＞
These evaluate how candidates respond to stress and trouble,
＜それは 飛行士達が ストレスや
トラブルに どう対応するかを➡
調べるための
｢グリーンカード｣というテスト＞
and are known as the green card test.
＜俺は それに
気づくことができた＞
I managed to figure out what was happening.
There are no bad guys in this room.
＜ここには 悪い奴はいない｡
それが分かったことで➡
That's all I need to sleep soundly tonight.
俺はもう 今日
ぐっすりなのだが…＞
＜ケンジ達のＢ班は この
やっかいなテストを➡
But I have to wonder how Kenji and the other Team B members are doing.
上手く切り抜けられて
いるのだろうか？＞
なすだ
(茄子田)入った 入った！
ノシー！
In! In!
So close!
I will rise,
climb,
and shoot through the atmosphere
My goal is zero gravity
Space Brothers
Waves of people flood the intersection
Like vague silhouettes they stream past incessantly
How do I look in their midst?
I don't know
Hiding my true intentions desperately
I dish out vague excuses
My ambitions of going to space, harbored for so long,
are frail and brittle
No matter how I turn the globus
I have no home where I end up
There's no point to looking on a map
I will rise,
climb,
and shoot through the atmosphere
until I can look down on the entire world
I will yell
and scream
with a heart of steel
that I am going to zero gravity
#18 Roo-ra! Kenji!
てじま
(手島)あ…また やってるね
まかべ
真壁さん｡
Oh, you're at it again, Makabe.
お～ かなり進んでる！
よく続けられるなぁ｡
Wow, you've made a lot of progress!
But I have no idea how you can stand it.
(ケンジ)実は こういうの
好きなのかも｡
Actually, I think I enjoy puzzles.
つか
でも 結構疲れない？それ｡
大丈夫？
But isn't it tiring?
Are you doing okay?
うん 疲れる｡でも やっぱり
やっちゃいたいんだよ｡だって…｡
Yeah, it's pretty tiring.
But I want to keep going.
After all...
(ｹﾝｼﾞ)⦅宇宙のパワー？⦆
Space power?
Yes, space power.
(女性販売員)⦅ええ 宇宙の
パワーです｡➡
ええ｡今 私が着けてる
これね とても珍しい➡
Yes.
I'm wearing a unique necklace made from the Duragram meteorite, yes.
いんせき
デュラグラム隕石で
できてるんですけどね ええ！➡
これが実は 宇宙と つながって
しんこう
ましてね｡信仰によって➡
This provides me with a connection to space.
If your faith is strong enough, you can receive power from space, yes.
宇宙のパワーを 受けることが
できるんですよ ええ⦆
(ｹﾝｼﾞ)⦅それは 興味深いですね
僕 宇宙好きなんで⦆
That's fascinating.
I've always been interested in space.
⦅でしょう！あなたのような方は
うちに入会して この石に➡
Exactly.
If you join us and start praying to this stone, you will find happiness.
祈り続ければ 必ず
幸せになれますよ｡➡
これ パンフレット｡ちなみに
この ＳＰＳは…➡
Here's a pamphlet.
By the way, SPS stands for "Space Power Stone."
スペース･パワー･ストーンの
略なんですけどね⦆
⦅これ 入会すれば 無料で
配布されますから ええ⦆
If you join, you'll get one free, yes.
(ｹﾝｼﾞ)⦅ちょっと質問が あるんです
けど その デュラ…⦆
I have a question first.
That's from the Dura...
⦅ええ デュラグラム隕石ですね
ええ！⦆
Yes, the Duragram meteorite, yes.
(ｹﾝｼﾞ)⦅そういう名前の隕石
初めて聞いたんですけど⦆
(女性販売員)⦅あら…⦆
I've never heard of that meteorite before...
Oh?
《あ～ぁ 俺はひねくれ者だな｡➡
Yep, I'm a total killjoy...
こんな連中
相手にしなきゃいいのに》
There's no need to push the issue.
⦅どこに落ちたやつですか？
その隕石⦆
Where, exactly, did that meteorite fall?
⦅えっ!?あ え～っと アメリカの
どっかだと思うんですけど⦆
Huh?
U-Um...
Somewhere in America, I believe.
⦅それは鉄隕石？それとも
マントル寄りのもの？⦆
(女性販売員)⦅あ い…⦆
Was it an iron meteorite? Or a stony-iron one?
What?
(ｹﾝｼﾞ)⦅それと 宇宙のパワーって
何ですか？➡
And what is this space power you speak of?
ダークエネルギーから きてるん
ですか？それとも 宇宙放射線の➡
Does it come from dark energy?
Or is it derived from cosmic rays?
エネルギーのことですか？
祈れば その隕石に そういう➡
Could you explain how prayer attracts the energy to that stone?
エネルギーが集まってくるって
いう そのメカニズムを詳しく…⦆
⦅え え～と…ですね⦆
W-Well...
⦅宇宙のことなら 何だって
知りたいんです 教えて下さい⦆
I want to know everything about space.
Please share your knowledge.
《ひねくれ者を通り越して
もう ねじれ者だな 俺は》
I'm turning into a devil's advocate...
I may sound like I know a lot about space, but I don't know much at all.
(ｹﾝｼﾞ)《自分だって 宇宙のこと
知ってるようで➡
何も知らないだろう｡
知りたいことの おおよそ半分は➡
Half the information I'm looking for can be found online or in books.
ネットや本で調べれば
分かることだ｡➡
どこにも載っていない
もう半分を知るためには➡
But as to the other half, I'll have to figure out
自分で考え出すか
経験するしかない》
the answer for myself or learn it from experience.
例えば 白いジグソーパズルを
完成させた時の気持ち…なんて➡
For example,
how does it feel when you finish a completely white puzzle?
That information can't be found anywhere.
どこにも載ってないだろ？
誰かに聞いたとしても➡
Someone else can tell you, but you won't really know how it feels.
それで 知ったことにはならない｡
それが 知りたくなったら➡
If you want to know,
自分でやるしかないよ｡宇宙へ
行きたい理由も同じだ｡
you have to experience it for yourself.
That's why I want to go to space.
なるほどね｡
みぞぐち
(溝口)真壁さん 他の
みんなが知りたいのは➡
I understand.
Makabe,
the rest of us aren't interested in that puzzle.
パズルより アラームの犯人と
今の時間ですよ！
We want to know the time and who's setting off the alarm.
きたむら
(北村)そうね…｡
That's true.
《それなら 今 俺が知りたいのは
この班が打ち解けあう方法だ》
In that case, I want to know how to get everyone on this team on the same page.
The last time I played rock-paper-scissors for food was grade school, for three-color Jell-O.
《ジャンケンでメシを
取り合うなんて➡
小学校の三色ゼリー以来だぜ》
ふるや
(古谷)ジャンケンを超える
公平な方法は あらへん！
Rock-paper-scissors is the fairest way to decide.
負けても文句言うなよ 南波！
Don't whine if you lose, Nanba.
俺 チョキ出すわ チョキ｡
I'm going to go with scissors.
フッ！その手に乗るかよ｡
Ha, you can't trick me.
《ど～せ グーだろ｡
サルに教わった》
You'll use rock like your monkey pals, right?
(六太･古谷)ジャンケン ホイ！
Rock, paper,
scissors!
ヒャハハ！よっしゃ～！
だから 正直に➡
Yes!
I told you I was going with scissors.
チョキ出す言うたやろ～｡どういう
思考で パーが出んねん！
Why would you throw paper?
とりあえず まあ 初回は
俺がガマンするということで｡
Well, I'll be the first to suck it up.
(せりか)本当に
ごめんなさい｡
I'm so sorry.
Nah, don't worry about it.
あ～…気にしなくていいよ｡➡
You already skipped a meal yesterday.
せりかさんは 昨日
食べてないんだから｡
ふくだ
(福田)なんだか
申し訳ないなぁ｡
I feel bad about this.
勝負は勝負や！オッチャン
甘やかしたらアカンでぇ｡
He lost fair and square, old timer.
Don't baby him.
《クソー…》
Damn...
《この日 立て続けに ｸﾞﾘｰﾝｶｰﾄﾞと
思われる事件が起こった》
That day, there was another probable green card-driven incident.
《まず トイレの水が
止まらなくなった》
The toilet wouldn't stop.
⦅おわっ！⦆
《福田さんと私で
何とか直したが➡
Fukuda and I managed to fix it,
途中までやっていた課題は
時間切れとなってしまった》
but we ran out of time on the task we were meant to be working on.
The culprit was likely Nitta,
にった
《犯人は おそらく新田だろう》
since his pants were wet for some reason.
《なぜか ズボンが濡れてたし
何より 普段の２割増しで➡
And he played it way too cool.
クールぶってやがる！》
(新田)みんな！
うろたえ過ぎだぜ｡
Guys,
you're overreacting.
《ズボン びしょ濡れのくせに！》
You realized your pants are wet.
《福田さんの時計 やっさんの
アラーム せりかさんの食料｡➡
Fukuda broke the clock.
Ya set off the alarm.
Serika used up the food.
そして 新田のトイレに続き
お米バラバラ事件発生！➡
And after Nitta fiddled with the toilet,
someone tore apart the bag of rice.
我らの大事な 残り少ない
お米ちゃんが バラ撒かれていた》
What little rice we had left was scattered across the floor.
みんなで 全粒拾うはめに｡
誰が犯人だろう？➡
We had to pick up every grain.
Who could have been responsible?
まだ 俺じゃねえってことは
誰かが ２枚目を➡
Since I haven't received a card, someone must have gotten two.
もらった計算になるな…》
And finally, it was my turn...
《そして ついに とうとう私にも
その時がやってきた！》
《グリーンカードデビュー！
新田や古谷は下手くそで➡
My green card debut!
Nitta and Furuya did a horrible job of concealing their involvement.
すぐ分かったけどな｡俺は
バレないように できるぞ～！》
I'll ensure no one suspects me...
《え～!?》
What?!
※ Do not respond if other members
ask about your behavior.
※ Do not tell anyone about the green
card or the orders you received.
"Shout abruptly, to startle the other members.
You must do this twice daily, until the last day..."
《最終日まで…何か 俺のだけ
方向性が違うんじゃないか？》
Until the last day?
Why is my card so different from the others?
《バレバレじゃん 犯人 俺って》
They'll all know it's me!
ポゥー！
なんや いきなり！
What was that?
ウホンッ！
《マイケル･ジャクソン…》
Michael Jackson.
Please understand, everyone...
《分かってくれよ みんな！
ＪＡＸＡの指示なんだ｡➡
I'm following orders from JAXA.
グリーンカードだからな
これは！》
I've been given a green card!
ホワチャー!!ワチャ！
What the hell?
おのれは…｡
ウホンッ！
《ブルース･リー…みんな
分かってくれてんのかな？》
Bruce Lee.
Do they understand what's going on?
What if they think I'm just a weird person?
《もしかして これ 普通に俺が
こういう人間だと思われて➡
終わりじゃねえのか!?
あ～ 他の指令に➡
Man, I hope they give me a different order...
変えてくんないかなぁ｡ケンジにも
こんな指令が 出てんのかな》
I wonder if Kenji's been given anything weird.
⦅ポウッ！⦆
《いや まさか やらねえだろ
あいつは》
No, he'd never do that.
(ｹﾝｼﾞ)また問題発生か…
これで３つ目だ｡
Another problem?
That's the third one.
管制(かんせい)に説明しても ずっと
｢中で解決するように｣としか➡
When we report the issues to Mission Control, they always tell us to solve it internally.
言わないし こうなると
今まで起きたこと全部➡
Which suggests that these problems have been happening at their direction.
管制の指示としか
思えなくなってきた｡
そ…そうかも しれないかも｡
Th-That might be it...
とみい
(富井)完全にダメ…みたいですね｡
Everything is gone...
(ｹﾝｼﾞ)溝口君は まだ僕を
疑ってるのか？
Do you still suspect me, Mizoguchi?
データが消えたんですよ！今まで
パソコンに記録してきた➡
The data was erased...
All the scores we've been recording for each member
みんなの点数が！
全員のパソコンから消えた｡
were wiped from every computer.
これで ２人を選ぶ基準が
なくなったんですよ！
We've lost our metric for selecting two astronauts.
こうなって一番喜ぶのは
最初から 点数制に➡
Isn't that rather convenient
for the one person who opposed using this method, Makabe?
文句をつけてた 真壁さん
だけじゃないですか！
疑われるのも 無理ないですよ｡
Why shouldn't I suspect you?
その ２人を選ぶっていう
ルールさ…｡
About that...
つるみ
(鶴見)⦅全員 意見一致のもと
５人の中から２人だけ➡
Come to a consensus
on the two members who would make the best astronauts.
宇宙飛行士に ふさわしい者を
選んで下さい⦆
｢２人選んで下さい｣って
言われたけど➡
We were told to choose two members,
選ばれた２人が宇宙飛行士です
とは誰も言ってないんだよ｡
but no one ever said that the two chosen would become astronauts.
そんなこと 議論したって
仕方ないでしょう｡
What's the point in arguing over that?
僕は最初から 僕らに宇宙飛行士の
決定権があるとは思っていない｡➡
I never thought we'd been given the power to select astronauts.
僕らは 宇宙飛行士について
いろいろ知っているようで➡
We sound like we know a lot about astronauts,
実は まだ何も知らないんだから｡
but we really don't know anything yet.
もしかしたらさ
｢選ばなきゃならない｣っていう➡
I've been thinking that the purpose of that statement
変なプレッシャーを
ずっと与え続けることが➡
was to make sure we would always be under pressure.
目的かもしれないよね｡
最近そう思えてきた｡
じゃあ お２人の考えだと
結局 宇宙飛行士は➡
So the two of you believe that JAXA will be selecting the astronauts,
ＪＡＸＡ側が選ぶもので
僕らに選ばせるというのは➡
and our choice will have no impact?
よきょう
余興だと言うことですね｡
そこまでは言い切れないけど
ＪＡＸＡが見たいのは➡
I wouldn't say that,
but JAXA isn't interested in seeing who's picked.
誰かが選ばれた
結果じゃなくて…➡
どんな風に僕らが選ぶのか
ってことだと思うよ｡
I believe that they're interested in seeing how we choose.
わかりました この中で選ぶ２人が
重要じゃないって言うなら➡
I understand.
If you say that it doesn't matter who's chosen,
ためしに真壁さんと手島さん…➡
Makabe and Teshima...
｢２人選出｣から
辞退して下さいよ｡
Please withdraw from the two member selection process.
うわ～っ 大変っすね Ｂ班…｡
Yikes...
Team B is a mess.
ほしか
(星加)ああ…それでも真壁君は
よく分かってるよ｡➡
Yes.
But Makabe understands what's happening.
彼の言った通りだよ｡
ここで選ばれる２人が➡
He's absolutely right.
There's no guarantee that the two from each group will become astronauts.
宇宙飛行士になれるとは限らない｡
ここでは あくまで
過程を見ているんだ｡
We're watching the process.
こく
(原田)はあ…酷な試験ですね｡
(星加)必要なことだよ｡
This is a harsh exam.
It's necessary.
じゃあ 宇宙飛行士には
いつ決まるんですか？ん？
When do we decide who will become astronauts?
たった１日｡
In one day...
(星加)全ては たった１日で
決まるんだよ｡
Everything will be decided in one day.
Makabe and Teshima...
⦅真壁さんと手島さん…
｢２人選出｣から➡
Please withdraw from the two member selection process.
辞退して下さいよ⦆
(ケンジ)ハァ ハァ ハァ…｡
ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…｡
《本当に辞退してやろうか…》
Maybe I really should withdraw.
桂馬のフンドシ どや？
Knight's loincloth.
What do you think?
ん～ そう来たか｡
Ah, so that's how you want to play...
《何やってんだ？》
What are you doing?
両取り 逃げるべからずと｡
Then I'll look for the third option.
Huh?
エア将棋ぃ!?
Air shogi?
そうや ジブンのエアそろばんとは
格が違うねん｡
マジかよ…｡
Yep.
This is on a whole different level than your air abacus.
Seriously?
えっ じゃあ 将棋盤とか
見えてんの!?駒とかさ｡
So you can actually visualize the shogi board?
And the pieces?
当たり前や！
ちょっと黙っててくれ｡
Of course... Could you shut up?
Shuffle, shuffle, shuffle, shuffle.
《バラバラバラバラバラ～ッ
バラバラバラ…バラバラ…》
《へっ》
じゃあ取らない｡３…五…角｡
あっ うまいねえ｡
Then I won't take either one.
Bishop, 3-5.
Oh, that's a good move.
(原田)あれっ 星加さん
休憩しないんですか？
Oh? Hoshika?
Aren't you going to take a break?
ああ 課題以外の こういう
自由時間も見ときたくてね｡
No, I want to observe how they spend their free time.
空き時間の過ごし方にも
その人が出るから｡
Their relaxation methods may provide insight to their characters.
(原田)これはＡ班ですね｡
This is Team A.
(星加)今 古谷君と福田さんは
エア将棋｡➡
Right now, Furuya and Fukuda are playing air shogi.
Nitta is doing yoga meditation.
新田君は ヨガで精神統一中だね｡
伊東さんは
何か本を読んでますね｡➡
Itou appears to be reading a book.
何の本だろ？拡大 拡大…｡
What is it?
Zoom in.
(原田)ロシア語講座！
(星加)なるほど｡
Russian Lessons!
I understand...
ＩＳＳには常にロシア人も
乗ってるからな｡
えらいな～伊東さん｡
Because the ISS always has Russians on board.
Itou's working hard.
勉強熱心！
She's a good student.
Oh?
(原田)南波君も本読んでる 意外！
Nanba's also reading a book.
That's a surprise.
(星加)何の本？
(原田)拡大します！
What's he reading?
Zooming in.
(星加)もうちょい下｡
Down a bit.
(原田)アメリカンジョーク…
に…ひゃ…く？
200 American Jokes...
(ケンジ)ハァ ハァ ハァ…｡
ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…｡
ハァ ハァ…｡
真壁さん もうずっと
走りっぱなしだけど➡
Makabe, you've been running for a long time.
止めなくていいのかな…｡
Shouldn't you take a break?
ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…｡
ふん｡
ふうか
(風佳)⦅こえ なに？⦆
Wat's dis?
⦅これはね うちゅうひこうし
っていうんだよ｡➡
This is an astronaut.
パパも次の試験に合格したら
これを着るかもしれないよ⦆
If Daddy passes the next exam, he'll get to wear that suit.
《って言っても
まだ わかんないか…》
I guess she can't understand that yet.
(風佳)⦅こえ パパ！⦆
This is Daddy!
ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…｡
ハァ ハァ…ハッ ハッ｡
溝口君 真壁さんと手島さんを➡
Mizoguchi, I think it's a bad idea to ask Makabe and Teshima to withdraw.
辞退させるってのは
さすがに よくないと思う｡
それは彼らが決めることですよ
北村さん｡
It's their decision to make, Kitamura.
僕は辞退を提案しただけで
強要したワケじゃありません｡
I was only providing them with some direction.
I never made any demands.
(ケンジ)ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…｡
真壁さん もう終わってますよ
問題…｡
Makabe, there aren't any more problems left.
(ケンジ)ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…｡
Finished
《あと２日で試験は
終わるってのに…➡
The exam ends in two days,
最後まで うまくいかないのか…
この班は｡➡
and this team still hasn't come together.
何も出来なかったな 俺…
この班のために｡➡
I was unable to do anything for this team...
ただ黙々と課題をこなして
点数つけて｡➡
We just silently worked on our tasks,
to improve our scores.
互いを認め合わず 課題で
一番になる作戦を練ってた…｡➡
Rather than working together,
we only focused on achieving the highest score!
これが 宇宙飛行士を
目指すってことか!?》
Is this what it means to become an astronaut?
(ケンジ)ハァ ハァ フゥ…｡
フゥ ハァ…フゥ ハァ…｡
(溝口)⦅辞退して下さいよ⦆
Please withdraw...
(ケンジ)《付き合ってられない》
I've had enough.
I think I really will withdraw.
《本当に辞退してやろうか…｡➡
その方がスッキリするんじゃ
ないか？あいつも…｡➡
I'll feel better that way.
And so will he.
｢ねじれ者｣だからな 俺は…》
Since I'm a devil's advocate.
きみ
(手島)溝口君 君さ…➡
Mizoguchi...
みんなの得点データが消えたのを
真壁君のせいにしてるけど➡
You accused Makabe of erasing everyone's scores.
それは違うって 本当は
わかってるんだろう？
But you must know it wasn't him.
…と言いますと？
What's your point?
(手島)１０日経って ある程度
順位は見えてたじゃん｡➡
After ten days, we all had a good grip on the current standings.
１位は君で…
真壁君が２位だった｡➡
You were first, and Makabe was second.
生き残れる２位の真壁君が
データを消すわけないだろ｡➡
Makabe was in the top two, so he had no reason to erase the data.
辞退はしないよ｡
He won't withdraw.
僕も 真壁君も｡
Neither of us will.
はっ…はぁ～｡
《疲れたな…》
I'm tired...
(ケンジ)《帰りたいって思うのは
俺だけか？》
Am I the only one who wants to go home?
(風佳)⦅かぺ～！⦆
Roo-ra!
ふ…ふふっ…かぺ～！か｡
Roo-ra, huh?
《何だろうな…かぺって｡➡
I wonder what it means.
かぺ…かぺ…風佳は
いつ言い出したんだっけ？➡
Roo-ra... Roo-ra?
When did Fuuka first say that?
｢行ってらっしゃい｣のことかな…
でも それが何で｢かぺ｣に？》
Was she saying goodbye?
But that doesn't sound similar at all.
Ah.
Fuuka...
(ケンジ)《風佳…》
(ユキ)⦅さあ～フーちゃん
そろそろ出るかな～？⦆
Come on, Fu.
You can do this...
⦅がんばれ～
ホラ が～んばれっ！➡
Good luck.
Here, good luck!
が～んばれ！が～んばれ！
が～んばれ！が～んばれ！⦆
Good luck!
⦅が～んばれ！が～んばれ！⦆
⦅か～ぺ か～ぺ か～ぺっ⦆
Good luck!
Roo-ra! Roo-ra!
Roo-ra!
⦅じゃあ
三次試験 行ってくるよ⦆
Well, I'm off to the third exam.
⦅行ってらっしゃい⦆
Be careful.
⦅かぺ～っ！⦆
Roo-ra!
｢がんばれ｣…か｡➡
Good luck?
Roo-ra
Good luck
ちゃんと意味もわかってて…｡
Then, she knew what she was saying.
ふっ ふふっ…ははっ…｡
《｢ねじれ者｣結構！》
So what if I'm a devil's advocate?
《それが俺だ！》
That's who I am.
《しょうがない
かぺるしかないな！》
I guess that settles it...
I'll have to count on my roo-ra.
The lens inside my eyes
went completely out of focus when I saw you
The signs of love flooded the occipital lobe of my cerebrum
The words the left side of my brain produced
brought my vocal cords to reverberation
Vigorously my confession traversed my tongue
May I love you?
May I really love you?
May I be beside you? (The concentration of my hormones rose)
(Dopamine overwhelmed me)
Can I hold your hand? (My blood circulation powered up)
Next time, on
Space Brothers
#19 The Day Before Goodbye
＜ワチャ！＞
＜私のひどいグリーンカードの
効力が いまだに続く中➡
I continue to follow my green card orders,
閉鎖環境での生活は
残すところ２日となった＞
as we're down to two days left in the sealed boxes.
＜そんな時…＞
(古谷)＜おい！➡
That's when...
Hey, there isn't enough food!
食い物 足りひんやないか＞
＜おかわり しすぎた＞
I shouldn't have had seconds...
＜私達は あり合わせの材料で
うどんをこねつつ➡
We use the remaining materials to make udon and talk about our interest in space.
宇宙への思いを語り合う＞
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"The Day Before Goodbye"
＜ここにいたんだ＞
They were here...
There were people who'd have been eager to come.
＜誘ったら 喜んで
ついて来てくれそうな連中が＞
ひびと
(日々人)パンパカパーン！
今週の➡
This Week's Space Photo
This week's space photo!
宇宙写真です！
すっげ～！
Awesome!